Hello everyone, I am Li Xinyuan, a Huawei lecturer.
In the last class, we talked about the technical knowledge of VRP,
And the upgrade method of AC and AP devices.
In that lesson, let's talk about WLAN's knowledge.
In public places, WLAN is now a wide range of contact methods.
As more and more people apply WLAN to access,
And our security requirements for WLAN will become higher and higher.
So in this section, I will tell you about it
Some of WLAN's access to security, data security and configuration security related knowledge.
Let's take a look together.
After studying this section, you can know what security threats WLAN faces,
Then deal with these security threats, what security defense mechanisms do we have.
Of course, in the end, I will list some of our common access certification methods,
This is also more practical.
In our daily work, we can follow different access certification methods
To distinguish which networks are safe enough and which networks are not safe enough.
In this way, our lessons are divided into five sections.
Safety threats and defense, access security, data security,
WLAN network use control and security configuration.
I will also take a detailed look at this safety configuration in the experiment to see how to configure it.
First of all, let's take a look at WLAN's security threat and defense.
Then we can see that in this topology, we have two APs,
What about these two APs are completely open.
So what threat will it encounter?
WiFi has no authentication, in this case,
Our attackers can connect our wireless network at will,
After connecting our wireless network, what about it?
He can be able to have the ability to the entire network equipment,
And users to attack.
So if you encounter unconfined wifi,
Everyone must be careful.
Then the second layer, the second security threat,
This is the encryption of this wireless data.
What does this mean?
In other words, we are in the process of surfing the Internet,
Our equipment, which is our STA,
Our terminal will communicate with our AP.
Then when communicating,
If our data is not encrypted,
Then other devices can also receive the electromagnetic waves we sent, right?
Then if there is no encryption,
You will know other devices,
What does our information contain.
Then maybe our privacy is intercepted in unintentional.
So the third is the border threat.
Let's see that there is an illegal AP here,
Then this illegal AP will release an same SSID,
For example, the SSIDs of this AP1 and AP2 are both Huawei.
So these two APs are legal.
But here is an illegal AP,
The SSID it uses is also Huawei,
The user may even be unknown to this illegal AP.
in this case,
The user's data will be sent directly to this illegal AP.
This hacker does not need to be caught in an empty mouth,
Directly we will send the data to the user themselves.
This is our common threats.
If the network is not authenticated, it will be attacked.
If the data is not encrypted,
It will be easy to be captured,
It is cracked by others to know what you transmitted.
The other is an illegal AP,
Plum directly on the illegal AP,
All your transmission data will be intercepted.
So the corresponding threats we just mentioned,
Then we now have some measures that correspond to their security defense.
The first one is the so -called security certification.
Everyone should have noticed this,
If we go to public, we
Will find a lot of wifi,
But most of the wifi need a password,
Then this guarantees that no casual devices can enter our network.
So for this security certification,
We can also choose two -way certification.
Users can verify the server,
The server can verify the user.
Then in this case,
We can verify whether this AP is illegal.
Then what,
A legal AP can also verify whether our user is illegal.
This is the so -called two -way certification.
This is our most common.
Then the second one,
Data encryption and integrity.
In other words, our data is in the process of transmission,
This should be encrypted.
If not encrypted,
Others can know our information in the empty mouth.
So,
Once complete, we use this hash,
And this MICS and CRC is guaranteed.
This way our server has received our data,
You can know whether our data has been tampered with.
Such a function.
Then the third is the so -called boundary security.
This boundary is safe,
Do not design in our class,
Just know it.
Border security,
We are divided into this wireless intrusion detection system,
There is also a wireless invasion defense system,
Referred to as WIDS and WIPS.
So in our class,
It focuses on security certification and data encryption and integrity.
The above is the content of the fifth section.